<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Purwa Wiadnyana &#8211; Blogging</title>
	<atom:link href="http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/author/purwa-wiadnyana/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 05:22:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>World Chess Champion Garry Kasparov on How to Build Confidence</title>
		<link>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/world-chess-champion-garry-kasparov-on-how-to-build-confidence/</link>
					<comments>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/world-chess-champion-garry-kasparov-on-how-to-build-confidence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Purwa Wiadnyana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 14:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Build Confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Champion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chess]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kasparov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/protheme/authorthemes/?p=479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Garry Kasparov and his long-time rival Anatoly Karpov—two of the greatest chess players of all-time—took their respective seats around the chess board. The 1990 World Chess Championship was about to begin. The two men would play 24 games to decide the champion with the highest scoring player being declared the World Chess Champion. In total, &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/world-chess-champion-garry-kasparov-on-how-to-build-confidence/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">World Chess Champion Garry Kasparov on How to Build Confidence</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Garry Kasparov and his long-time rival Anatoly Karpov—two of the greatest chess players of all-time—took their respective seats around the chess board. The 1990 World Chess Championship was about to begin.</p>



<p>The two men would play 24 games to decide the champion with the highest scoring player being declared the World Chess Champion. In total, the match would stretch for three months with the first 12 games taking place in New York and the final 12 games being played in Lyon, France.<br><br>Kasparov started off well, but soon began to make mistakes. He lost the seventh game and let multiple victories slip away during the first half of the tournament. After the first 12 games, the two men left New York with the match tied at 6-6. The New York Times reported that “Mr. Kasparov had lost confidence and grown nervous in New York.”<a href="https://jamesclear.com/kasparov-confidence#"></a></p>



<p>If Kasparov was going to retain his title as the best in the world, it was going to take everything he had.</p>



<h2 id="title_0">“Playing Kasparov Chess”</h2>



<p>Josh Waitzkin was a chess prodigy as a child and won multiple U.S. Junior Championships before the age of 10. Along the way, Waitzkin and his father had the opportunity to connect with Garry Kasparov and discuss chess strategy with him. In particular, they learned how Kasparov dealt with remarkably difficult matches like the one he faced against Karpov in the 1990 World Chess Championship.</p>



<p>Waitzkin shares the story in his book,&nbsp;<a href="https://jamesclear.com/book/the-art-of-learning">The Art of Learning</a>&nbsp;(<a href="https://jamesclear.com/audiobook/the-art-of-learning">audiobook</a>).</p>



<p><em>Kasparov was a fiercely aggressive chess player who thrived on energy and confidence. My father wrote a book called Mortal Games about Garry, and during the years surrounding the 1990 Kasparov-Karpov match, we both spent quite a lot of time with him.</em></p>



<p><em>At one point, after Kasparov had lost a big game and was feeling dark and fragile, my father asked Garry how he would handle his lack of confidence in the next game. Garry responded that he would try to play the chess moves that he would have played if he were feeling confident. He would pretend to feel&nbsp;</em>confident,<em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;</em>hopefully<em>&nbsp;trigger the state.</em></p>



<p><em>Kasparov was an intimidator over the board. Everyone in the chess world was afraid of Garry and he fed on that reality. If Garry bristled at the chessboard, opponents would wither. So if Garry was feeling bad, but puffed up his chest, made aggressive moves, and appeared to be the manifestation of Confidence itself, then opponents would become unsettled. Step by step, Garry would feed off his own chess moves, off the created position, and off his opponent&#8217;s building fear, until soon enough the confidence would become real and Garry would be in&nbsp;</em>flow<em>…</em></p>



<p><em>He was not being artificial. Garry was triggering his zone by playing Kasparov chess.</em></p>



<p>—Josh Waitzkin,&nbsp;<a href="https://jamesclear.com/book/the-art-of-learning">The Art of Learning</a></p>



<p>When the second half of the World Chess Championship began in Lyon, France, Kasparov forced himself to play aggressive. He took the lead by winning the 16th game. With his confidence building, he rattled off decisive wins in the 18th and 20th games as well. When it was all said and done, Kasparov lost only two of the final 12 games and retained his title as World Chess Champion.<a href="https://jamesclear.com/kasparov-confidence#"></a></p>



<p>He would continue to hold the title for another 10 years.</p>



<h2 id="title_1">“Fake It Until You Become It”</h2>



<p>It can be easy to view performance as a one-way street. We often hear about a physically gifted athlete who underperforms on the field or a smart student who flounders in the classroom. The typical narrative about underachievers is that if they could just “get their head right” and develop the correct “mental attitude” then they would perform at the top of their game.</p>



<p>There is no doubt that your mindset and your performance are connected in some way. But this connection works both ways. A confident and positive mindset can be both the cause of your actions and the result of them. The link between physical performance and mental attitude is a two-way street.</p>



<p>Confidence is often the result of&nbsp;<a href="https://jamesclear.com/growth-mindset">displaying your ability</a>. This is why Garry Kasparov&#8217;s method of playing as if he felt confident could lead to actual confidence. Kasparov was letting his actions inspire his beliefs.</p>



<p>These aren&#8217;t just feel-good notions or fluffy self-help ideas. There is hard science proving the link between behavior and confidence. Amy Cuddy, a Harvard researcher who studies body language, has shown through her groundbreaking research that simply&nbsp;<a href="https://jamesclear.com/body-language-how-to-be-confident">standing in more confident poses can increase confidence and decrease anxiety</a>.</p>



<p>Cuddy&#8217;s research subjects experienced actual biological changes in their hormone production including increased testosterone levels (which is linked to confidence) and decreased cortisol levels (which is linked to stress and anxiety). These findings go beyond the popular fake it until you make it philosophy. According to Cuddy, you can “fake it until you become it.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/world-chess-champion-garry-kasparov-on-how-to-build-confidence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When the 80/20 Rule Fails: The Downside of Being Effective</title>
		<link>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/when-the-80-20-rule-fails-the-downside-of-being-effective/</link>
					<comments>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/when-the-80-20-rule-fails-the-downside-of-being-effective/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Purwa Wiadnyana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 14:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[of Being Effective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the 80/20 Rule Fails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Downside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[When]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/protheme/authorthemes/?p=476</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Audrey Hepburn was an icon. Rising to fame in the 1950s, she was one of the greatest actresses of her era. In 1953, Hepburn became the first actress to win an Academy Award, a Golden Globe Award, and a BAFTA Award for a single performance: her leading role in the romantic comedy&#160;Roman Holiday. Even today, &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/when-the-80-20-rule-fails-the-downside-of-being-effective/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">When the 80/20 Rule Fails: The Downside of Being Effective</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Audrey Hepburn was an icon.</p>



<p>Rising to fame in the 1950s, she was one of the greatest actresses of her era. In 1953, Hepburn became the first actress to win an Academy Award, a Golden Globe Award, and a BAFTA Award for a single performance: her leading role in the romantic comedy&nbsp;<em>Roman Holiday</em>.</p>



<p>Even today, over half a century later, she remains one of just 15 people to earn an “EGOT” by winning all four major entertainment awards: Emmy, Grammy, Oscar, and Tony. By the 1960s, she was averaging more than one new film per year and, by everyone&#8217;s estimation, she was on a trajectory to be a movie star for decades to come.</p>



<p>But then something funny happened: she stopped acting.</p>



<p>Despite being in her 30s and at the height of her popularity, Hepburn basically stopped appearing in films after 1967. She would perform in television shows or movies just five times during the rest of her life.</p>



<p>Instead, she switched careers. She spent the next 25 years working tirelessly for UNICEF, the arm of the United Nations that provides food and healthcare to children in war-torn countries. She performed volunteer work throughout Africa, South America, and Asia.</p>



<p>Hepburn&#8217;s first act was on stage. Her next act was one of service. In December 1992, she was awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom for her efforts, which is the highest civilian award of the United States.</p>



<p>We will return to her story in a moment.</p>



<h2 id="title_0">Efficient vs. Effective</h2>



<p>You get one, precious life. How do you decide the best way to spend your time? Productivity gurus will often suggest that you focus on being effective rather than being efficient.</p>



<p>Efficiency is about getting more things done. Effectiveness is about getting the&nbsp;<em>right</em>&nbsp;things done. Peter Drucker, the well-known management consultant, once encapsulated the idea by writing, “There is nothing so useless as doing efficiently that which should not be done at all.”</p>



<p>In other words, making progress is not just about being productive. It&#8217;s about being productive on the right things.</p>



<p>But how do you decide what the “right things” are? One of the most trusted approaches is to use the Pareto Principle, which is more commonly known as the 80/20 Rule.</p>



<p>The 80/20 Rule states that, in any particular domain, a small number of things account for the majority of the results. For example, 80 percent of the land in Italy is owned by 20 percent of the people. Or, 75 percent of NBA championships are won by 20 percent of the teams. The numbers don&#8217;t have to add up to 100. The point is that the majority of the results are driven by a minority of causes.</p>



<h2 id="title_1">The Upside of the 80/20 Rule</h2>



<p>When applied to your life and work, the 80/20 Rule can help you separate “the vital few from the trivial many.”<a href="https://jamesclear.com/the-downside-of-being-effective#"></a></p>



<p>For example, business owners may discover the majority of revenue comes from a handful of important clients. The 80/20 Rule would recommend that the most effective course of action would be to focus exclusively on serving these clients (and on finding others like them) and either stop serving others or let the majority of customers gradually fade away because they account for a small portion of the bottom line.</p>



<p>This same strategy can be useful&nbsp;<a href="https://jamesclear.com/inversion">if you practice inversion</a>&nbsp;and look at the sources of your problems. You may find that the majority of your complaints come from a handful of problem clients. The 80/20 Rule would suggest that you can clear out your backlog of customer service requests by firing these clients.</p>



<p>The 80/20 Rule is like a form of judo for life and work. By finding precisely the right area to apply pressure, you can get more results with less effort. It&#8217;s a great strategy, and I have used it many times.</p>



<p>But there is a downside to this approach, as well, and it is often overlooked. To understand this pitfall, we return to Audrey Hepburn.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/when-the-80-20-rule-fails-the-downside-of-being-effective/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>30 One-Sentence Stories From People Who Have Built Better Habits</title>
		<link>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/30-one-sentence-stories-from-people-who-have-built-better-habits/</link>
					<comments>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/30-one-sentence-stories-from-people-who-have-built-better-habits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Purwa Wiadnyana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 13:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[30 One-Sentence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Built Better Habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[From People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Have]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Who]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/protheme/authorthemes/?p=473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this article, I&#8217;d like to share 30 “one-sentence stories” about building better habits. (They are not all&#160;exactly&#160;one sentence, but they are very short.) None of these stories are mine. They were sent to me by readers of&#160;Atomic Habits. My hope is that these examples will illustrate how real people are putting the book into &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/30-one-sentence-stories-from-people-who-have-built-better-habits/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">30 One-Sentence Stories From People Who Have Built Better Habits</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">In this article, I&#8217;d like to share 30 “one-sentence stories” about building better habits. (They are not all&nbsp;<em>exactly</em>&nbsp;one sentence, but they are very short.)</p>



<p>None of these stories are mine. They were sent to me by readers of&nbsp;<a href="https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits">Atomic Habits</a>. My hope is that these examples will illustrate how real people are putting the book into practice. They will show you what people are actually doing to build good habits and break bad ones. And hopefully, they will spark some ideas for how you can do the same.</p>



<p>I have divided the stories into categories that roughly correspond to different sections or ideas in the book.</p>



<h2 id="title_0">Identity-based habits</h2>



<p>One of the central ideas in the book is the concept of building&nbsp;<a href="https://jamesclear.com/identity-based-habits">“identity-based habits”</a>, which essentially recommends focusing on the type of person you wish to become rather than the outcome you wish to achieve.</p>



<p>One reader named Roland used the idea to improve his eating habits.</p>



<p>“I stopped eating unhealthy food via identity change,” he wrote. “I tried many times in the past, but it became easy — natural — only after I had made the conscious decision that I want to be someone who eats healthy. Instead of aiming for&nbsp;<em>I want to stop eating bad food</em>, I tried changing the mindset to&nbsp;<em>I am someone that eats healthy and lives a healthy life</em>. It changes how you approach things.”</p>



<p>Another reader named Robert employed this idea to help him quit smoking. He wrote, “I recently stopped smoking and the difference between&nbsp;<em>I don&#8217;t smoke</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>I can&#8217;t smoke</em>&nbsp;is a powerful trainer of my brain. The positive message of&nbsp;<em>I don&#8217;t smoke</em>&nbsp;is that I have not “given up” anything. I am not sacrificing a pleasure. I am investing in my future happiness and wellbeing.”</p>



<p>Like most strategies in the book, the concept of identity-based habits can be combined with other habit building tactics. For instance, one reader used an external reward of $10 to reinforce the desired identity. “I told myself,&nbsp;<em>I am no longer a drinker</em>. Then, after each day of non-drinking, I gave myself $10 to buy something nice rather than poison (like clothes and household items). Today, I no longer need the allowance and I&#8217;m six years sober.”</p>



<p>Chapter 2 of&nbsp;<a href="https://atomichabits.com/">Atomic Habits</a>&nbsp;covers these strategies in much greater detail.</p>



<h2 id="title_1">Changing the Cues</h2>



<p>Another way you can change a habit is by identifying and altering the cues that prompt your behavior. This is precisely what many readers have done.</p>



<p>One woman named Lisa cultivated a reading habit by increasing her exposure to books. “I&#8217;ve read more books by continually having 20-30 books on hold at the library,” she said. “It saves time on browsing for books. I always have new things to read with a three-week deadline.”</p>



<p>Heather used a similar strategy to reinforce the simple habit of drinking more water. “I use color and placement for visual reminding and motivation. I poured water in a bright aqua water bottle – my favorite color – and placed it on my nightstand so I couldn’t miss it when I woke up.”</p>



<p>Other readers have done the opposite. They&nbsp;<em>reduced</em>&nbsp;exposure to&nbsp;<em>negative</em>&nbsp;cues. One man named Max managed to eliminate his e-cigarette habit. “I quit e-cigarettes with a combination of determination and also quitting coffee at the same time, which was a trigger for me as I&#8217;d smoke and drink coffee together in the morning.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/30-one-sentence-stories-from-people-who-have-built-better-habits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Proven Path to Doing Unique and Meaningful Work</title>
		<link>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/the-proven-path-to-doing-unique-and-meaningful-work/</link>
					<comments>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/the-proven-path-to-doing-unique-and-meaningful-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Purwa Wiadnyana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 13:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[and Meaningful Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Path]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Proven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[to Doing Unique]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/protheme/authorthemes/for-a-more-creative-brain-follow-these-5-steps-copy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nearly all great ideas follow a similar creative process and this article explains how this process works. Understanding this is important because creative thinking is one of the most useful skills you can possess. Nearly every problem you face in work and in life can benefit from innovative solutions, lateral thinking, and creative ideas. Anyone &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/the-proven-path-to-doing-unique-and-meaningful-work/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Proven Path to Doing Unique and Meaningful Work</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Nearly all great ideas follow a similar creative process and this article explains how this process works. Understanding this is important because creative thinking is one of the most useful skills you can possess. <a href="#">Nearly every problem you face in work and in </a>life can benefit from innovative solutions, lateral thinking, and creative ideas.</p>



<p>Anyone can learn to be creative by using these five steps. That&#8217;s not to say being creative is easy. Uncovering your creative genius requires courage and tons of practice. However, this five-step approach should help demystify the creative process and illuminate the path to more innovative thinking.</p>



<p>To explain how this process works, let me tell you a short story.</p>



<h2 id="a-problem-in-need-of-a-creative-solution"><br>A Problem in Need of a Creative Solution</h2>



<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aenean commodo ligula eget dolor. Aenean massa. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec quam felis, ultricies nec, pellentesque eu, pretium quis, sem. Nulla consequat massa quis enim. Donec pede justo, fringilla vel, aliquet nec, vulputate eget, arcu. In enim justo, rhoncus ut, imperdiet a, venenatis vitae, justo. Nullam dictum felis eu pede mollis pretium. Integer tincidunt. Cras dapibus. Vivamus elementum semper nisi. Aenean vulputate eleifend tellus. Aenean leo ligula, porttitor eu, consequat vitae, eleifend ac, enim. Aliquam lorem ante, dapibus in, viverra quis, feugiat a, tellus. Phasellus viverra nulla ut metus varius laoreet. Quisque rutrum. Aenean imperdiet. Etiam ultricies nisi vel augue. Curabitur ullamcorper ultricies nisi. Nam eget dui. Etiam rhoncus. Maecenas tempus, tellus eget condimentum rhoncus, sem quam semper libero, sit amet adipiscing sem neque sed ipsum. Nam quam nunc, blandit vel, luctus pulvinar, hendrerit id, lorem. Maecenas nec odio et ante tincidunt tempus. Donec vitae sapien ut libero venenatis faucibus. Nullam quis ante. Etiam sit amet orci eget eros faucibus tincidunt. Duis leo. Sed fringilla mauris sit amet nibh. Donec sodales sagittis magna. Sed consequat, leo eget bibendum sodales, augue velit cursus nunc,</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/the-proven-path-to-doing-unique-and-meaningful-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>For a More Creative Brain Follow These 5 Steps</title>
		<link>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/for-a-more-creative-brain-follow-these-5-steps/</link>
					<comments>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/for-a-more-creative-brain-follow-these-5-steps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Purwa Wiadnyana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Follow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For a More]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[These 5 Steps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/protheme/authorthemes/?p=462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nearly all great ideas follow a similar creative process and this article explains how this process works. Understanding this is important because creative thinking is one of the most useful skills you can possess. Nearly every problem you face in work and in life can benefit from innovative solutions, lateral thinking, and creative ideas. Anyone &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/for-a-more-creative-brain-follow-these-5-steps/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">For a More Creative Brain Follow These 5 Steps</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-drop-cap">Nearly all great ideas follow a similar creative process and this article explains how this process works. Understanding this is important because creative thinking is one of the most useful skills you can possess. <a href="#">Nearly every problem you face in work and in </a>life can benefit from innovative solutions, lateral thinking, and creative ideas.</p>



<p>Anyone can learn to be creative by using these five steps. That&#8217;s not to say being creative is easy. Uncovering your creative genius requires courage and tons of practice. However, this five-step approach should help demystify the creative process and illuminate the path to more innovative thinking.</p>



<p>To explain how this process works, let me tell you a short story.</p>



<h2 id="a-problem-in-need-of-a-creative-solution"><br>A Problem in Need of a Creative Solution</h2>



<p><br>In the 1870s, newspapers and printers faced a very specific and very costly problem. Photography was a new and exciting medium at the time. Readers wanted to see more pictures, but nobody could figure out how to print images quickly and cheaply.</p>



<p>For example, if a newspaper wanted to print an image in the 1870s, they had to commission an engraver to etch a copy of the photograph onto a steel plate by hand. These plates were used to press the image onto the page, but they often broke after just a few uses. This process of photoengraving, you can imagine, was remarkably time-consuming and expensive.</p>



<p>The man who invented a solution to this problem was named Frederic Eugene Ives. He went on to become a trailblazer in the field of photography and held over 70 patents by the end of his career. His story of creativity and innovation, which I will share now, is a useful case study for understanding the 5 key steps of the creative process.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/02/11/for-a-more-creative-brain-follow-these-5-steps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Should You Need to Read Book Everyday</title>
		<link>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/01/15/why-should-you-need-to-read-book-everyday/</link>
					<comments>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/01/15/why-should-you-need-to-read-book-everyday/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Purwa Wiadnyana]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 14:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Everyday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Should]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Why]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[You Need to]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/protheme/authorthemes/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s no secret that the digital industry is booming. From exciting startups to global brands, companies are reaching out to digital agencies, responding to the new possibilities available. However.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It’s no secret that the digital industry is booming. From exciting startups to global brands, companies are reaching out to digital agencies, responding to the new possibilities available. However, the industry is fast becoming overcrowded, heaving with agencies offering similar services — on the surface, at least.</p>



<p>Producing creative, fresh projects is the key to standing out. Unique side projects are the best place to innovate, but balancing commercially and creatively lucrative work is tricky. So, this article looks at how to make side projects work and why they’re worthwhile, drawing on lessons learned from our development of the ux ompanion app.</p>



<p>People think focus means saying yes to the thing you’ve got to focus on. But that’s not what it means at all.</p>



<p>Producing creative, fresh projects is the key to standing out. Unique side projects are the best place to innovate, but balancing commercially and creatively lucrative work is tricky. So, this article looks at how to make side projects work and why they’re worthwhile, drawing on lessons learned from our development of the ux ompanion app.</p>



<p>Why Integrate Side Projects?<br>Being creative within the constraints of client briefs, budgets and timelines is the norm for most agencies. However, investing in research and development as a true, creative outlet is a powerful addition. In these side projects alone, your team members can pool their expertise to create and shape their own vision — a powerful way to develop motivation, interdisciplinary skills and close relationships.</p>



<p>Building into the identity and culture of an agency can also lead to new client work. These projects act as a road map, showing clients exciting new technologies and ideas that will differentiate you from competitors. One of our earliest projects turned our website into a brochure, optimized for the first iPad’s touch interactions. By demonstrating the final product, we went on to win a project to create a similar product for a new client.</p>



<p>A significant shift in mindset is required to support either type of side project — weighing the longer-term, incremental benefits against committing what would otherwise be immediately billable time. Many agencies do this with a time-bound model of 80% client time versus 20% time, inspired by Google’s successes with Gmail and Google Reader which they have since (tellingly) phased out. I’d instead recommend the following guidelines.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://wdnyana.github.io/brand-website/2022/01/15/why-should-you-need-to-read-book-everyday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
